So in a world of electric cars, in this
video, we're gonna be taking a look at a
$20,000 hybrid, $120,000 hybrid, and a $2
million hybrid car. So this video is part
an explainer, part a chance to drive some
really sick cars. Shout out to Triple F
Collection. We'll get there. Anyway,
unless you guys have been living under a
rock, you've seen that electric cars have
been having a bit of a renaissance
lately, surging in popularity, till the
number 1 best sold new car on Earth is
electric. But, they are still very much a
new technology. Like they're obviously
awesome with instant torque and no
emissions and fast acceleration, but they
have these huge heavy batteries and they
take forever to recharge and there's not
enough infrastructure for everyone to own
them. So there's this window now where it
makes a lot of sense that maybe for most
people a hybrid is actually the best
option. Interesting. So I don't think
anyone's buying the Corolla for speed or
power. I mean, if I'm being honest, it's
actually still pretty zippy. So this car
starts at $24,000 and it's a hybrid
purely, purely for efficiency. So the
basics of this hybrid system, and many
others in the same class, is that the
wheels can be driven by the gas engine or
the electric motor or both. So this
Corolla Hybrid has a 1.8 liter engine and
1 electric motor at the front axle that
deliver a combined 138 horsepower. And
it's powering the electric motor with a
pretty small 1.6 kilowatt hour battery.
So at low speeds, you've probably been in
a car like this, the car goes totally
electric, the gas engine turns off, but
once you go over a certain speed or use a
certain amount of power, then it's going
to fire up the gas engine again and it
couples it with the electric motor. Then
anytime you're braking or coasting,
that's when it charges the battery back
up. It's as you're slowing down, it
captures some of that energy. So it never
actually needs to be plugged in to charge
up that small battery. And this system is
good for literally 50 miles per gallon.
When you drive this car, you literally
have a game score, an eco score as you
drive of, if you can slow down and roll
onto your accelerations better and roll
to a stop more easily, you can gamify
efficiency in this car to get your
maximum miles per gallon. So it actually
divides it up. I have my eco zone, so I'm
driving and if I get my little bar in the
eco zone, I'm doing a good job. And then
I have starts, cruises and stops. I've
gotten my eco score pretty high not to
brag, but I've seen it in the 70s, which
is pretty sick I don't know what happens
when I get to a hundred But what I do
know is the better I get that score the
more miles per gallon I get But yeah,
pretty much everything about the rest of
this car is designed around that
efficiency. It's aerodynamic enough that
it slips through the air. It's got tires
that have a low rolling resistance. It
doesn't have these like sticky grippy
tires. That's what that's actually
against efficiency in this case. So if
you're looking for a reason why someone
would buy a hybrid today, it's because
they're not trying to charge a huge
battery every night in their garage or
rely on the grid or rely on finding
public chargers. It's because they just
want better gas mileage and they want to
spend less, not 0, but less on gas today.
But you already know, these cars are
obviously very utility focused. They're
for people who just are going places,
right? But what if you're more after the
ultimate driving machine, something a
little more versatile, then you can spend
a little more money and get something
like this. All right, so this car starts
at about $100,000 a little over, and this
car is a hybrid for versatility. So the
idea is this is a BMW 750E. There's a
bunch of vehicles in this class, but
yeah, you've spent enough money now at
this point that you can reap the benefits
of both gas and electric. So this hybrid
system has a bit more hardware to
accomplish 2 different goals. So there's
a 3 liter straight 6 engine making around
300 horsepower and a medium sized 14.4
kilowatt hour larger battery powering a
roughly 200 horsepower electric motor. So
you're totaling around 500 horsepower. So
once again, it can drive using both gas
and electric, just like the Toyota. But
now there's enough battery capacity that
you can also drive fully electric at
Totally normal everyday driving speeds up
to like 30 miles on a charge without ever
turning on the gas engine and then also
Unlike the Corolla This is a plug-in
hybrid so you can directly plug the car
into a wall to replenish the battery and
just keep driving around on electric as
long as You want to with 0 gas use so it
does everything in the Toyota does but
more I do feel like plug-in hybrids at
this moment in time are the 1 that make
the most sense for the most people that I
see driving them. Because if you have a
short commute, let's say you have a 10
mile commute every day, and you just plug
in at a charger at work or in your garage
every night or during work in the
daytime, You can just straight up never
pay for gas again and drive it just like
an electric car But on the off chance you
do need to drive further go for a road
trip Or just do something more than your
normal 10 mile commute you have all the
benefits of a gas car Thankfully these
hybrids also have 1 crucial piece of the
electric car, which is regenerative
braking, which means it's going to be
able to recuperate a lot of the energy
once I've gotten up to speed and start
filling up the battery as I'm driving. So
there's a little graph on the dash you
can see here, which means as I accelerate
and I take energy out of the battery it
goes up but as I decelerate it's actually
blending and friction braking with
regenerative braking and if I drive
around like this long enough especially
if I go down hills and brake a lot I will
actually start adding to the charge of
this battery too. But you know how
electric cars also have that party trick
of instant torque available at any RPM
and any speed? Well, the hybrid should
benefit a little bit from that too. So
because this motor is powerful enough and
the battery is big enough to provide the
voltage, yes in the sportiest mode this
car also when you floor it gets that
initial hit from the electricity and then
follows with the surge of the rest of the
power from the gas engine. Oh and 1 of
the things I say a lot on the autofocus
channel, or I've said before, is there
are certain types of cars that are best
to go electric and because of how much
batteries weigh, cars that are already
heavy are the best ones to go electric.
So like this is a big four-door luxury
sedan. There is no attempt at making this
a small car. It's huge, it's got lots of
space, it's soft, it's cushy. This is a
great type of car to go electric which is
why the i7 is good. But yeah, there are
lots of other versions of this. The RAV4
hybrid, the Toyota Prius Prime hybrid,
all sorts of other plug-in hybrids. Yeah,
if I were to recommend 1 version for more
people like this, you still get all the
nice plushy suspension and all the tech
in the car and all the screens and the
way it drives. It's the same thing, but
more accessible. You don't have to have a
plug in your garage. So all that is fun.
That's... I get it. It's versatile. This
is why they call it the ultimate driving
machine. But you can always spend more.
You can always spend more. And when you
do, you end up in the territory of
specialists. And this is definitely a
specialist. Just give me a second. 1
second, just want to... Okay. Now close
that.
I've just got eyes for you. No other
could enchant me, darling, like you do.
I've just got eyes for you.
So this car costs 2 and a half million
dollars And it's a hybrid purely for
performance, which I mean, you could
probably tell just by looking at it, but
also by the fact that I'm sitting in the
middle of the car right now. I have to
get used to this. This is the McLaren
Speedtail, okay? So McLaren's done this a
few times. 1 center driver's seat, 2
passenger seats, and just a whole lot of
calibration for me for this insane
driving position. But yeah, this thing is
a hybrid. It's technically a hybrid. So
this hybrid system is pretty crazy. It's
very focused on literally just going as
fast as physically possible, which is
just about maximizing power and
minimizing weight. So there's already a
twin turbo 4 liter V8 engine pushing out
750 plus horsepower, but then they've
also designed a special small but super
high powered 1.6 kilowatt hour battery
that powers a single electric motor by
itself that generates an extra 300 more
horsepower. So the total is now over a
thousand horsepower and that motor is
basically just being used to help spin
the wheels Even faster than the engine by
itself could there is no electric only
mode There is no situation where the gas
engine ever shuts off. There are no
efficiency goals here This is actually
really similar to the turbocharged hybrid
setups. You literally see in Formula 1
today It's just about going fast. So
here's a couple of those hilariously
over-engineered pieces of this car. First
of all, this is the only car I've ever
actually driven that's shipped with
cameras instead of side-view mirrors for
even better aerodynamics, of course
They've also got the electrochromic glass
roof tint and windshield tint instead of
moving fabric pieces. But then also the
active arrow on the back of this car is
not just like regular pivoting parts or
spoilers or anything like that. But it's
literally bending the carbon fiber
bodywork and all of the paint and
coatings with it up and down when you're
under braking to assist with slowing
down. It's that's insane if you can see
what's happening here. And this is also
the only car I've ever seen with a
wireless charger. That's right. The
McLaren Speedtail wireless charges So the
battery is at the bottom of the car and
it's small enough that if the driver
doesn't park Exactly over the right spot
in their garage. It's not a huge deal
because again, it's a small battery it
shouldn't take too long and inductive
charging has never been particularly
efficient but it'll eventually work and
no I don't think that this would fly for
any fully electric car today. Everything
about the outside of this car is designed
it's sculpted to just cut through the air
And that's how it does 0 to 186 miles an
hour faster than a Bugatti Chiron and 250
miles an hour in a straight line. Now I'm
going to let you in on a little secret
about these super, super fast electric
cars. They need a huge battery to
realistically make that happen, Right?
Let's take Tesla Model S Plaid for
example. A thousand horsepower, crazy
high power output from the battery. But
in order to do that they need to give it
this huge 100 kilowatt hour battery so
that when you export all that power You
don't just drain the battery super
quickly. You can keep driving like a
normal person. So that's why you have
these super high horsepower electric
cars, but they always come with the
sacrifice of weight. They're always
heavy. The Lucid Air, it's fighting its
weight. The EV6 GT, It's fighting how
heavy it is. With a supercar like this,
it's not fully electric all the time, and
so they're willing to put in a tiny
battery that exports a ton of power and
basically drains it in seconds. So I'm
going to show you something with this
real quick. Right now I have 100% of my
battery. I'm going to do just a quick
little pull and see just what a couple of
seconds of electric assisted acceleration
will do. All The way down to 74% battery,
just from that little acceleration, 100
to 74. And now it's already, it's going
right back up to 100. It's almost 100
again because I'm driving and
recuperating that energy and Now it's a
hundred This is super high-tech stuff and
it actually has a lot of parallels to
what we see in Formula 1 Believe it or
not those Formula 1 cars that we're
watching on TV today. Those are small
turbocharged Hybrid powertrains, I kind
of want to do that again That's what the
F1 cars are doing out there. They are
recovering energy as they brake, and they
are spending energy when they accelerate.
And I guess that's the difference between
this and the Rimac Nivera. You remember,
you probably have seen the video I did
with the quickest electric car in the
world, the Rimac Nivera, which yes does
have a big heavy battery. It weighs like
5,000 pounds, like a Model S. The crazy
thing about that car, and that's an
anomaly, is that it has 4 electric
motors, which you can kind of think of as
being treated like gears, but not really.
This will have a higher top speed simply
because it just keeps gearing up. 7-speed
gearbox and it pulls all the way through
up to 250 miles an hour. If you want a
hybrid supercar you can kind of have both
fast and quick in the same car. This is
fast and quick. I mean it's not
razor-sharp fully electric quick but it's
close and it's yeah it's the fastest It's
1 of the fastest cars you can possibly
build. Yeah, so I guess my point here
with the whole video is yes, I still
fully believe electrification is the
future at every level of cars But in the
meantime, it's pretty clear that hybrids
make a lot of sense. I mean, right under
our noses the whole time. That's about
it. I got to drive a speed deal.